Guide to the Duke University Oral History Program Collection, 1973-1978, 1992 RL.00338
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Tulsa Race Riots, 1978; 3
  - Pittman, Mr. and Mrs. I.S. - interviewed by Scott Ellsworth, 1978-07-26; 142
    - Audiocassette original (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0122)
    - Audiocassette backup copy (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0033)
  - Whitlow, Henry - interviewed by Scott Ellsworth, 1978-06-06; 143
    - Audiocassette original (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0133)
    - Audiocassette backup copy (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0044)
  - Williams, N.C. - interviewed by Scott Ellsworth, 1978-07-20; 144
    - Audiocassette original (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0134)
    - Audiocassette backup copy (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0045)
  - Williams, Seymour - interviewed by Scott Ellsworth, 1978-06-02; 145
    - Audiocassette original, tape 1 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0131)
    - Audiocassette backup copy, tape 1 of 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0042)
    - Audiocassette original, tape 2 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0132)
    - Audiocassette backup copy, tape 2 of 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0043)
  - Williams, William D. - interviewed by Scott Ellsworth, 1978-06-07; 146
    - Audiocassette original, tape 1 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0129)
    - Audiocassette backup copy, tape 1 of 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0040)
    - Audiocassette original, tape 2 of 2 (Box 2, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0130)
    - Audiocassette backup copy, tape 2 of 2 (Box 5, Audio-cassette RL00338-CS-0041)
- Transcripts Series, 1974, 1978, 1992
  Scope and Contents note
  The series includes eighty transcripts of some, but not all, of the interviews in the North Carolina Civil Rights Movement Audiotapes Subseries. Some transcript files include notes on the corresponding interview, usually providing background information about the interviewee. These transcripts are arranged alphabetically by last name of the interviewee; transcripts for multiple interviews of one person are arranged chronologically. RESTRICTIONS: Since there are no release forms accompanying these transcripts, patrons must seek the permission of copyright holders before publishing quotes from these sources.
  - Anonymous (black male), 1978, July 10, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Adams, Charlotte, 1974, Aug. 21 (Box 6)
  - Augustine, Joe, 1974, June 10, 14 (Box 6)
  - Baker, Quinton, 1974, June 2, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - "Barnabus" and Darryl Franks, 1978, May 14 (Box 6)
  - Blackwood, Roy, undated (Box 6)
  - Bordeaux, Walter, undated (Box 6)
  - Bowers, Wayne and Mary, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Brown, Bob, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Bulkley, Joel, 1974, June 14 (Box 6)
  - Bynum, Sheila, 1974, June 5 (Box 6)
  - C-Man, 1978, Aug, 12, 16 (Box 6)
  - Caldwell, Hilliard, 1974, June 4 (Box 6)
  - Calhoun, Richard, 1974, June 3 (Box 6)
  - Campbell, Sharon Sitton, undated (Box 6)
  - Carr, Warren, 1978, Jan. 31 (Box 6)
  - Carswell, John, undated (Box 6)
  - Chestnutt, undated (Box 6)
  - Clarence and wife, 1974, June 16 (Box 6)
  - Clark, A. D., undated (Box 6)
  - Cobb, Collier, 1974, June 14 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Thomas, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Cotten, Charles Pearl, undated (Box 6)
  - Curitan, William, 1974, Aug. 25 (Box 6)
  - Cusick, Pat, 1974, June 10, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Dansby, David, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Dunne, John, 1974, June 8 (Box 6)
  - Foushee, Braxton, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Foushee, Charles, 1974, June 5 (Box 6)
  - Foushee, James, 1974, June 9 (Box 6)
  - Foushee, Vivian, 1974, June 4 (Box 6)
  - Foushee, W. R., 1974, June 4-5 (Box 6)
  - French, Virginia, 1974, June 5 (Box 6)
  - Gulick, Margared, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Grant, Jim, 1978, July 10 (Box 6)
  - Hearn, James, 1974, June 10 (Box 6)
  - Herzog, Frederick, 1974, June 10 (Box 6)
  - Hicks, Charles and "Tink" Farrell, 1974, June 8 (Box 6)
  - Hill, George Watts, undated (Box 6)
  - Hill, Watts, 1974, June 14 (Box 6)
  - Jones, Charles, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Klopfer, Peter, 1974, June 5 (Box 6)
  - Lassiter, Gaitha, 1974, Aug. 21 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Howard, 1974, Aug. 27 (Box 6)
  - Malone, C. C., 1974, Aug. 23 (Box 6)
  - Manley, J. R., 1974, June 12 (Box 6)
  - McClamrock, Sandy, 1974, June 5 (Box 6)
  - McDougall, C. A. and wife, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - McKissick, Floyd, 1978, Oct. 2 (Box 6)
  - Minor, Paul, 1974, June 12 (Box 6)
  - Moore, Douglas E., 1978, Jan 28 (Box 6)
  - Nye, Kemp, 1974, June 10 (Box 6)
  - Osborn, Robert, 1974, June 4 (Box 6)
  - Pendergraft, Don, 1974, June 10 (Box 6)
  - Perry, Velma, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Phelps, Jake, 1974, June 6 (Box 6)
  - Queen, Ann, 1974, June 11 (Box 6)
  - Richardson, John, June 7, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Sanford, Terry, August 29, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Schumaker, Jim, June 6, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Shepherd, Ann, July 10, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Smith, David, June 5, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Reginald, 1974, June 4, 13, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Spearman, Walter, 1974, June 5 (Box 7)
  - Straley, Joe, 1974, Aug. 17 (Box 7)
  - Strowd, Gene, 1974, Aug. 27 (Box 7)
  - Sturdivant and Jones, 1974, June (Box 7)
  - Templeton, Eugene, 1978, Aug. 1 (Box 7)
  - Timberlake, Phyllis, 1974, June 5 (Box 7)
  - Wager, Paul, 1974, Aug. 7 (Box 7)
  - Wallace, James, 1974, June 12 (Box 7)
  - Walters, Adelaide, 1974, June 10 (Box 7)
  - Weaver, Susie, 1974, June (Box 7)
  - White, undated (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Hugh, 1974, June 5 (Box 7)
  - Yopp, Abbot P., 1992, Aug. 15 (Box 7)
- Research Files Series, 1960-1964
  The Research Files Series consist of five files of research material on the North Carolina Civil Rights Movement, as well as one file of tape and transcript lists. The materials include a bibliography on the Durham sit-ins, compiled by Elyse Gallo; articles and speeches by Governor Terry Sanford; a file on the movement from 1960 to 1964; and three files of related background information.
  - Research 1960-1964 (Box 8)
  - Background, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Durham Sit-ins Bibliography (Box 8)
  - Terry Sanford (Box 8)
  - Tapes and transcript lists (Box 8)